Cameron Ray

Full Stack Web Developer

cameronsray@gmail.com
(601) 942-4333
San Francisco, CA
linkedin.com/in/cameronsray
github.com/upsmancsr I cameronsray.dev

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer specializing in JavaScript, React, Node, SQL, Python, and C. 3+ years of experience in mechanical sales engineering and software sales to engineering customers provides a strong foundation for understanding product requirements and customer needs as they relate to software development.

SKILLS

Languages

- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- Python
- SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite)
- . .

Frameworks/Libraries

- React
- Redux
- · Node.js
- Express
- · Knex.js

EDUCATION

Lambda School Full-Stack Web Development

July 2018 - April 2019

- Wrote production code for Front End and Back End
- Completed 100% of weekly Sprint Challenges
- Front End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Less.js
- Back End: Node.js, Express, SQL, Python, Django, C
- Utilized Git workflows, agile development, and project management skills to deliver finished products as an individual and team member

University of Mississippi BS, Mechanical Engineering

Minors in Math and Spanish May 2015

 Designed and built multi-terrain robot and competed at ASME regional robotics competition

PROJECTS

Chattr - Live Chat for Sales and Customer Service

https://labs10-webchat.netlify.com/

https://github.com/Lambda-School-Labs/labs10-webchat

- Top contributor on 5-person team to build live chat app similar to Intercom
- Planned and built all database models; built key API endpoints and db query methods; built front end live chat dashboard integrated with Socket.io; implemented Stripe subscription billing; integrated Firebase auth with key components and admin functions
- Languages and frameworks included React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Socket.io, Stripe API, Firebase Auth, Material UI, Styled Components

Use My Tools - Rental Marketplace for Tools

https://github.com/upsmancsr/Use-My-Tools-CSR

- Built the full stack for a web app similar to Turo
- Languages and frameworks included React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Firebase Auth and Firestore realtime database, Material UI, Google Places API

LambdaMUD - Multi-User Dungeon Game

https://github.com/upsmancsr/LambdaMUD-Client

• Built out the front end client for a multi-user dungeon game integrated with Python/Django backend; used Pusher Web Sockets for live messages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Development Representative

Instrumental, Inc. I Los Altos, CA I October 2017 - May 2018

 Expanded sales funnel focused on Hardware Product Development teams; worked with internal teams to adapt marketing and strategic initiatives to customer needs

Sales Development Representative

Aviatrix Systems, Inc. I Palo Alto, CA I May 2017 - October 2017

- Conducted outbound sales to establish qualified meetings for Enterprise sales reps; spearheaded implementation of Drift live chat platform to convert previously untracked website visitors into inbound leads
- Established expertise in cloud networking and infrastructure product landscape to provide insight to sales reps on deal potential

Sales Director

AmberBox, Inc. I Mountain View, CA I October 2016 - February 2017

- Built initial sales funnel and helped generate first 5 proposals
- Consulted with dozens of prospects to understand needs and relay to engineering team building first-generation product

Sales Engineer

Delta Thermal Solutions, Inc. I Jackson, MS I October 2015 - October 2016

- Designed and specified HVAC and heat transfer system packages for consulting engineers based on thermal, mechanical, and electrical requirements
- Created competitive bids according to engineering specs for new projects
- · Conducted end-user training on booster pumps and hydronic boilers
- · Closed equipment sales totaling 38% of company revenue